<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-11-12T16:57:09+03:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">S-Ential Technologies</title><subtitle>Welcome to S-Ential Technologies. Our company is focussed on providing IT solutions to small and meduim sized businesses across the East African region. S-Ential Technologies offers SaaS as well as customized softwares that help businesses leverage potential by increasing revenues, efficiency, speed and security. Our website url is https://www.s-entialtechnologies.com. Our products are powered by Amazon Web Services (AWS).
 </subtitle><entry><title type="html">5 Reasons To Use a Professional Email Address</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/category/blog/technology/insights/202102/reasons-to-use-a-professional-email-address" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Reasons To Use a Professional Email Address" /><published>2021-02-24T12:00:06+03:00</published><updated>2021-02-24T12:00:06+03:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/category/blog/technology/insights/202102/reasons-to-use-a-professional-email-address</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/category/blog/technology/insights/202102/reasons-to-use-a-professional-email-address">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Email address is very important when doing business. It can be tempting to try and save money by using free email options, but when you’re running a business it’s important to have a professional email address, and it will be well worth the money you spend. This article will explain the reasons why.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-credibility-and-trust&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Credibility and Trust&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In business, maintaining a professional image is important for keeping your customers’ trust and appearing credible online. 
Routing your emails through your business’s domain name shows that you are well-established, legitimate and professional. Using a branded address like jason@hnm.com definitely looks more professional than jasonstephenson1982@hotmail.com and is likely to make customers feel more comfortable dealing with you.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-clear-link-to-your-website&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Clear link to your website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a domain or branded email gives your business a corporate image. Domain or branded email addresses create a positive image and makes it easier for people to remember your business.
This also contributes heavily to reassuring them that you are a legitimate and established business, and engenders trust. Any email you send, or any time you leave your contact details with someone, you’re also giving them an easy link to your website, which can boost your marketing efforts.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-reduce-the-risk-of-being-marked-as-spam&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Reduce the risk of being marked as spam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spam filters are much more aggressive when it comes to free accounts because spammers are more likely to use them. For that reason, having a professional email address connected to your own domain is a trust marker. A professional email address reduces the risk of your business emails bouncing or being sent straight to the trash can.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-staying-organized&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Staying Organized&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can easily organize your mail according to departments or other groups for managing your workload for example sales@yourdomain.com, support@yourdomain.com. This can further reinforce credibility for your business.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-collaborate-with-your-team&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Collaborate with your team&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Domain email addresses make it easy to use add-ons such as shared calendars which make collaborating with your colleagues much easier, creating a healthy work environment.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
While on the surface you might appear to be saving money by using a free email address for your business, you’ll often find it’s costing you dearly in other ways like consumer confidence, your business’s credibility, and even in productivity. If you are not sure how to create your business’ domain or branded email addresses, contact your website’s hosting company for directions on how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may want to check out our wholesome packages if you don’t have a domain name or website. For more information, view our pricing page by clicking the pricing button.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Irene</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Email address is very important when doing business. It can be tempting to try and save money by using free email options, but when you’re running a business it’s important to have a professional email address, and it will be well worth the money you spend. This article will explain the reasons why.</summary></entry></feed>